

Contact

Phone 503-847-7504

Email rcpragati2@gmail.com

Address 466 NE Patricia Ann Pl, Hillsboro, OR 97006

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/pragatirathore

Portfolio https://pragatipdx.github.io/

Expertise

Technologies

Java 8, Python, SQL, Microservices, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Shell, React, JavaScript, HTML5, JUnit, JDBC, JMS, Selenium

• Frameworks

SpringBoot, MyBatis/ Hibernate, Flask, Cucumber

• Automation Tools

SoapUI, Nexus, Jenkins, TeamCity, Postman, SonarQube

• Development Tools

IntelliJ, Eclipse, VSCode, Spring, Tool Suite, Thomson Reuters eGRC

Version Control

GIT, Perforce

Platform

Windows, UNIX

Known Tools

Jira, Trello, Confluence, Service Now, Splunk

Pragati Rathore

Software Engineer

Over 5+ years of experience as a Software Engineer working in the Financial Technology Industry. Extensive experience in leadership roles in the complete SDLC process including requirement definition, designing, interface coding, debugging, testing and deployment in a fast-paced agile (scrum) driven environment. Deep knowledge and established background in Microservices, Python, DevOps, Java web and Cloud technologies. Strong abilities in efficient database design and performance optimization with experience in advanced Oracle PL/SQL development. Expert Level Proficiency in CI/CD pipelining and DevOps tools for end-to-end delivery of application.

Experience

Intel Corporation | Hillsboro, OR | June 2022 - Present

Software Development Intern

- Designed and developed management of symbols & binaries for Intel's symbol store
- The resolution prevents manual intervention to locate symbol files & re-analyze crash dumps- saving lost engineering time & delayed bug resolutions. (>70 workhours/ qtr)
- Implemented retention-based purging of symbols freeing 37% of storage.
- Designed enablement of AWS Graviton3-based workload recipes.
- Technologies: Python, Kubernetes, Docker, Cloud Platform: AWS, Cumulusbackend, Jenkins, Groovy, Docker, GIT, Microsoft Symbol Server

Barclays | Pune, India | July 2018 - August 2021

Senior Software Engineer

- Developed an in-house Microservice-oriented Java web-based application to decommission third-party legacy tools, reducing license costs and enhancing performance and user interaction.
- Designed an automation framework integrated with CI/CD pipeline to reduce work hours
- Delivered weekend classroom training on Java programming, DevOps, and corporate framework to peers and leads to upskill workforce as part of the Digital Transformation program.
- Technologies Java8, SpringBoot, MyBatis, Junit, Rest API, AngularJS, SQL Server, Jenkins, Docker, SonarQube, Cloud platforms: AWS and Azure

Infosys I Pune, India | March 2018 - June 2018

Senior Java Developer

- Performed re-designing and deployment of financial domain client's (HSBC Bank) Indian region website across multiple middle eastern countries.
- Technologies: Java8, Angular, Node.js, Javascript, Shell Script, MySQL, Jenkins, Docker, Cloud platforms: AWS.

Tata Consultancy Services | Pune, India | September 2015 - February 2018

Java Developer

- Worked on Compliance Solutions for a Multinational Investment Bank with technologies inclusive of Java 8, Maven, and SQL Database.
- Responsible for end-to-end delivery of modules using Agile Methodologies, in a fast-paced agile(scrum) driven team environment. Well-versed with Jira
- Automation/Build tools- Nexus, Jenkins, TeamCity, SonarQube.
- Version control systems- Git and Perforce

Education

September 2021 - Present

Masters in Computer Science Portland State University GPA: 3.89 / 4

August 2011 - June 2015 **Bachelors in Computer Science**Rajiv Gandhi Prodyogiki Vishwavidyalaya

GPA: 3.9 / 4

Language

English

Hindi

Leadership Experience

Barclays | 2020 | Workforce Transformation Program | Pune, India

• **Trainer** - Delivered weekend classroom training to peers and leads to upskill them on Java programming, DevOps and corporate framework

Tata Consultancy Services | 2016 | Training Program | Hyderabad, India

 Head Coordinator - Assisted Training Head Officer of the Java Training program in mentoring trainee associates, coordinating assessments, attendance, and documentation.

Hitkarini Training and Placement Camp | 2015 | RGPV, India

• College Ambassador - Coordinated a job fair with 5000+ student participation and 100+ recruiters meet up in an open campus drive for a 4 days event.

Awards and Achievements

- Top performer of the Year 2020, Barclays. Awarded outstanding ranking in Year-End Performance Review 2020
- Top performer of the Year 2019, Barclays. Awarded outstanding ranking in Year-End Performance Review 2019
- TCS On the Spot Award 2017 for stewardship, process improvement, and HR enablement.
- TCS Business Customer Recognition for Value addition to the organization by Performance Enhancement Utility - 2016
- Awarded apprenticeship of Scientist DR R.S Bharadwaj and tour to scientific centers in India in the event "Vigyan Manthan" under Mission Excellence Program, MP council of science & Technology, India - 2010